# Rita Morais

#### Graphic & Web Designer

rita.dpmorais@gmail.com

# Summary

I am graphic designer with a passion for code, currently in the process of becoming a Front End Designer. With a BA in Communication Design (with Marketing and Design Management) and currently finishing a Nanodegree in Front End Design. I have two years experience in Editorial Design, Illustration and UX/UI design. I have a very plastic, graphic illustrational side, but also a very "engineer" oriented, direct and practical one, therefore I like facing each challenge as a new one, learning from previous experiences but not only reproducing something I'm comfortable doing, I try to always improve my work.

# Skills & Expertise

Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
InDesign
Illustration
HTML
CSS
Theatre
Final Cut Pro
Adobe Creative Suite
JavaScript
jQuery

# Experience

#### UX/UI Designer at Tasboa

September 2014 - Present (9 months)

- Rethinking and redesigning interfaces and improving user experience - Working under fast changing conditions - Receiving current feedback and effectively adapting results

#### Graphic/Web Designer at The Love Food

2014 - 2015 (1 year)

- Designed company website: www.thelovefood.pt - Redesigned company blog: www.blogthelovefood.com - Designed company's graphic material: product packaging, flyers, online graphic promotional material

## Head Teacher at Minerva Language School

March 2013 - March 2014 (1 year 1 month)

- Head Teacher and Content Developer - Worked under very demanding always changing environment - Developed ability to improvise and quickly adapt a plan to the current needs

#### Editorial Designer and Content Developer at Jibun Mirai Associe Co. Ltd.

October 2011 - March 2013 (1 year 6 months)

- Designed layout and material for language textbooks - Designed graphic material for lessons

#### Education

#### **Udacity**

Front End Web Developer NanoDegree, Web Page, Digital/Multimedia and Information Resources Design, 2014 - 2015

#### Escola Superior de Artes e Design

Bachelor of Communication Design, Graphic Design, Editorial Design, Marketing, 2008 - 2011 Activities and Societies: Students' Association Graphic Department for one year

#### Certifications

#### **Cambridge English Certificate**

University of Cambridge License 06CPT0055036 December 2006

### Languages

English(Native or bilingual proficiency)Portuguese(Native or bilingual proficiency)

French (Elementary proficiency)

Japanese (Elementary proficiency)

#### Interests

Illustration, Performance, Dance, Music

# Volunteer Experience

#### External Volunteer at TEDx Lausanne

February 2015 - Present (4 months)

Design works, Registration and General work.

# Projects

### **Catter Javascript Arcade Game**

March 2015 to Present

Members:Rita Morais

Designed graphics and coded the game functions fully in javascript Give it a try! It's fun!

#### The Love Food Blog Redesign

# Members:Rita Morais

Redesigned former's blog, migrated to wordpress

# **Rita Morais**

Graphic & Web Designer

rita.dpmorais@gmail.com



Contact Rita on LinkedIn